hello and welcome to the 26 tutorial on
how to break image script 2.
and in this tutorial i want to show you
how to use a
pretty important thing in gscript 2
called public
and i'll explain how what that does when
we get to it
the first thing i want to do is
create an npc
let's open up this npc here you can just
ignore these two at the bottom
okay
first let's add
client side
and add function
on created
as soon as the npc is created let's
set image
button
up dot png
uh
let's make a new function called
function on action
left mouse
now what on function on function left
mouse does
is if you left click the npc then
whatever is in these brackets will run
you can also replace this with
on action right mouse
and it'll do the same thing but with the
right mouse button
let's keep it at left
and in here let's add
show
text
which is the same which is very similar
to show image
and we'll put 200 which is the index
same thing as show image if it's under
200 it appears for everyone if it's over
it appears for just you
and we'll put
we'll put this
dot x comma this dot y
next what we have to put is
the uh
the font we want to use
let's just put in
times
new
roman baltic you can look at all of your
fonts that girl has if you go to
options
going to
general i think
one of these
and one of them oh
oh here it is font here you can see all
the fonts that girl has i'm using
times new roman baltic anyway
i just close that
and
open up this again
oops
okay so what we want to do is
put this font here
put comma then null
this part is very important right now
now this little
parameter it's not very important then
what we're going to put is some text
that we want like
hi
then end the brackets put dot
layer is equal to 4.
yeah showing text in jscript2 isn't very
easy
showing text anywhere you want i mean
the index the x the y
the font
this part is not very important but you
can i'm not sure what it does when i
replace it with something like
cb i've saw i've seen this on the forums
before i'm not sure what it does but we
can just put null here and the font and
then layer is equal to four what this
dot layer equals before does is it makes
it so that you can actually see the show
text
um i'm pretty sure the layer has to do
with what is above what like
what images are above other images and
something like that
but we'll just put it leave it at four
that's what i recommend
anyway let's close this
save it and i'll up the level
i'm just going to straighten that out
upload testing and we can see a button
here it was made by david k by the way
and if we click it with the left mouse
it'll say hi here at the top
left of the screen
of the
screen
you may be wondering we put this dot x
and this dot y why is it not
showing the text over the npc
well
show
text is a special little function where
any kind of x coordinate or y coordinate
is
has to do with pixels for example this
dot x and this dot y
what tile is this on maybe
uh
8 comma 10 well it'll put it at the
eighth pixel and down 8 pixels
so what you want to do is put times 16
which is how many pixels are in a title
time 16
and that will make the
show text appear over the mp over the
mpc
save that
and i'll upload
i click it and it will appear over
npc
uh
there is a way to make it so that it
appears based on the tile number but
let's not get into that now because it
has to do with image manipulation
because show text is technically an
image
anyway
after this
let's add
set image
button down
dot png
so it'll change the image as soon as we
click it then it'll sleep two seconds
then we'll just copy paste this here
and over here where it says stuff we'll
just put blanket out so
the text will just disappear
and here we'll put it back to
buttonup.png
so if we close this save then i upload
when we click the mpc
as you can see the npc image changes
then it
pops back up
we click it it says hi pops down pops up
both of the images were made by david k
like i said
now let's say we want
to not have to put show text whenever we
want to say
i mean should we ever want to say hi or
something we want it to be in a
different you know
we just want to put a little command and
it'll do it for us
well there's a way to do that
first let's change this to something
like
quest completed so as soon as you click
the button it'll complete your certain
quest or whatever you're wanting to do
then i'll close this
bring this down and i'll open up
some weapons
straighten this out
now both of these weapons i already have
added to myself
and we're going to use
well we don't need both of them let's
just use this one and we're going to use
uh this weapon
to show
quest completed whenever we run a
certain command in any npc or
any weapon to do this let's put client
side then put
public which is a new command i was
talking about
public uh
what should we put
on
no
let's put let's make up our own function
function
on
quest completed
brackets parentheses now this function
doesn't really do anything because it's
not a function that's built in it's our
own function
and
what public does is it allows this
function to be accessed by any other
weapon and any npc
that we want and to do that is i'll show
you in a second
let's put in something like
i'll just copy the
show text from the npc
and put it here
so that as soon as i
i can call this
function and it'll say this also let's
replace this.x because you know weapons
don't have this.x
we'll place it with mouse.x
and then mouse.y
so whenever we click the npc it'll just
you know the text will appear on our
mouse
now
alone this weapon isn't going to do
anything
but if we want to access this function
here's what we have to do
we have to go into the mpc or whatever
weapon we want to use
and we have to add
um
well first i want to take out this
show text we don't need that here
and we'll add um
find
weapon
brackets the name of the weapon and my
name on my weapon is uh
one second
zm underscore test one
zm
underscore test one
next we end the bracket then put dot
because we're gonna input uh
the name of the function which is on
quest
completed
yes i think it is
yeah it is
next
we're going to end it with some brackets
here
and that's it
this is going to
be used to enter a function from a
different weapon
keep in mind that
public needs to be here or else this
function will not be found because
you know
it isn't being it's not able to be
accessed by other weapons
so we put this here
we close it oh we only want to get this
out too
close this
and here
let's put
sleep
two
and then put show image again so we can
you know erase the old show image
and we'll just blank this out right
here we click apply
and i'll just lower this here
i'm going to save this
level
and upload it
so let's see if that works
it says quest completed but not on our
mouse
i wonder why
let's replace this with
take out the dot maybe
yeah there we don't need the dot with
mouse x so yeah as you can see
in this npc there is no
command called show text
there's nothing there's only find weapon
and then on quest completed show that is
a function
then in the weapon
zm test one let's just close this gm
test one we have a public function under
the name of on quest completed which
we're going toward and in this function
we're putting show text which is making
the text appear waiting two seconds and
putting show text again to make it
disappear
so this is how you use function you can
use function to call
any kind of weapon
from any other weapon or any other npc
you know it's pretty flexible this way
you
keep in mind that the player must have
this weapon attached to them
if it's going to be used if this weapon
were not attached to me like it was off
of me
then you know you could not use this
special little
fine weapon
thing here
anyway that's the end of this tutorial
and i hope you understand how to use
public along with this new function
called on action left mouse
and i'll see you next time